Julia Freedman

Remote | Cincinnati, OH www.linkedin.com/in/juliaFhttps://github.com/julsfreedman

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Full stack software developer with over 22 years of professional experience in various industries. Pursuing a career in front and/or back-end enterprise software development. Eager to bring unique insights into the existing technical solutions and ways to improve upon and create superior systems for businesses and nonprofits.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office Suite • Filemaker Pro • Google Suite • SharePoint • Slack • Prezi • Docusign contract lifecycle management • MongoDb • Express • React

Node.js • HTML • CSS • JavaScript • GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Krause & Kinsman Law Firm, Remote

2021-present

Legal intake Agent

- Communicate with potential new clients who have requested our services to gather information in order to present their claim to our attorneys for a free case evaluation.
- Manage files in Law Ruler software.

FDS Bank, Remote 2018-2020

Fraud Analyst

- Researched and resolved inquiries via the credit systems and other media to respond to unauthorized activities on accounts.
- Reviewed, investigated, and determined action to be taken for all data in fraud queues for proprietary accounts.
- Promoted from Fraud Prevention Service Ambassador to Fraud Claims analyst.

The Union Institute & University, Cincinnati, OH

2014-2016

Assessment Coordinator

- Collected, retrieved, and archived data regarding program effectiveness utilizing university designated software.
- Aggregated, analyzed and disseminated data results.
- Supported faculty and administrators in the development of guidelines, templates, policies, and rubrics to facilitate university-wide implementation of assessment
- and e-portfolios for students.
- Prepared faculty and staff workshops: prepared resource and training material; coordinated real and virtual space.
- Administered electronic surveys with an emphasis on privacy.
- Participated on the Women in Union Scholarship committee.

EDUCATION

Per Scholas, Remote

9/2022 - 1/2023

Software Engineering program

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

College of Arts and Sciences | B.A. in Psychology 3.5 GPA

1998-2002

CERTIFICATIONS

Series 7 (General Securities License) - expired Series 63 (Uniform Securities License) – expired Notary Public, State of Hawaii - expired

TribleByte Front-End Engineering Certificate https://triplebyte.com/tb/julia-f-08swo5k/certificate